njng.com 2019-06-24

# Privacy Statement for New Jersey Natural Gas

**PRIVACY DISCLOSURES**  
Last Updated – January 28, 2015

**Information Collection and Use**  
New Jersey Resources Corporation and its subsidiaries (collectively, the “Company”) are the sole owners of the information collected on our Web site. The Company collects personally identifiable information from our users at several different points on our Web site.

_Application Forms_  
If you subscribe to a service requiring financial information on our site, we may require that you provide certain personally identifiable information, including your name, address, phone number, credit card number or banking information. This information is necessary to process your application and to contact you.

_Surveys or Contests_  
From time to time we may provide you the opportunity to participate in contests or surveys on our site. If you participate, we will request certain personally identifiable information from you. Participation in these surveys or contests is voluntary and you therefore have a choice whether or not to disclose this information. The requested information typically includes contact information (such as name and mailing address), and demographic information (such as ZIP code). We use this information to notify contest winners and award prizes.

We may use a third-party service provider to conduct these surveys or contests. We will not share the personally identifiable information you provide through a contest or survey with other third parties unless we give you prior notice and choice.

**Communications from the Site**

_Special Offers and Updates_  
We will occasionally send you information on products and services. Out of respect for your privacy, we present the option not to receive these types of communications. Please see “Choice and Opt-out.”

_Newsletters_  
If you wish to subscribe to our newsletter(s), we will use your name and e-mail address to send the newsletter to you. Out of respect for your privacy, we provide you a way to unsubscribe. Please see the “Choice and Opt-out” section.

_Service-related Announcements_  
We will send you strictly service-related announcements on rare occasions when it is necessary to do so. For instance, if our service is suspended for maintenance, we might send you an e-mail. You may opt-out of these communications. Please see “Choice and Opt-out.”

_Customer Service_  
We will communicate with you in response to your inquiries to provide the services you request, and to manage your account. We will communicate with you by e-mail or telephone, in accordance with your wishes.

_Profile_  
We store information that we collect through cookies, log files and clear gifs to create a “profile” of your preferences. We do not share your profile with other third parties.

**Information Sharing and Disclosure**

_Service Providers_  
We may use other third parties to provide services on our site. When you sign up for a service, we will share information as necessary for the third party to provide that service.

_Legal Disclaimer_  
We reserve the right to disclose your personally identifiable information as required by law and when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights and/or to comply with a judicial proceeding, court order or legal process served on our Web site

**Choice/Opt-out**  
We provide you the opportunity to ‘opt-out’ of having your personally identifiable information used for certain purposes, when we ask for this information. If you no longer wish to receive our electronic service-related alerts, newsletter or promotional communications (other than materials included in your monthly bill), you may opt-out of receiving them by following the instructions included in each newsletter or communication or by e-mailing us at [sitesupport@njng.com](mailto:sitesupport@njng.com), or you may contact us by telephone at 800-221-0051 or 1415 Wyckoff Road, P.O. Box 1464, Wall, NJ 07719 to opt-out.

**Log Files**  
As is true of most Web sites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp and clickstream data.

We use this information, which does not identify individual users, to analyze trends, to administer the site, to track users’ movements around the site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole.

**Cookies**  
A cookie is a small text file that is stored on a user’s computer for record-keeping purposes. We use cookies on this site. We use both session ID cookies and/or persistent cookies. We use session cookies to make it easier for you to navigate our site. A session ID cookie expires when you close your browser. A persistent cookie remains on your hard drive for an extended period. You can remove persistent cookies by following directions provided in your Internet browser’s “help” file. If you reject cookies, you may still use our site, but your ability to use some areas of our site, such as contests or surveys, may be limited.

This privacy statement covers the use of cookies by our Company only and does not cover the use of cookies by any third party.

**Clear Gifs**  
We employ a software technology called clear gifs (a.k.a. Web Beacons/Web Bugs), that help us better manage content on our site by informing us what content is effective. Clear gifs are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies, and are used to track the online movements of Web users. In contrast to cookies, which are stored on a user’s computer hard drive, clear gifs are embedded invisibly on Web pages and are about the size of the period at the end of this sentence.

We use clear gifs in our HTML-based e-mails to let us know which e-mails recipients have opened. This allows us to gauge the effectiveness of certain communications and the effectiveness of our marketing campaigns. If you would like to opt-out of these e-mails, please see “Choice and Opt-out.”

**Links to Other Sites**  
This Web site contains links to other sites that are not owned or controlled by our Company. Please be aware that we are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites.

We encourage you to be aware when you leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each Web site that collects personally identifiable information.

This privacy statement applies only to information collected by this Web site.

**Bulletin Boards/Chat Rooms**  
If you use a bulletin board or chat room on this site, you should be aware that any personally identifiable information you submit there can be read, collected or used by other users of these forums, and could be used to send you unsolicited messages. We are not responsible for the personally identifiable information you choose to submit in these forums.

**Access to Personally Identifiable Information**  
If your personally identifiable information changes, or if you no longer desire our service, you may correct or update it by signing into My Account and making the change or by contacting us by telephone or postal mail at the contact information listed below.

**Security**  
The security of your personal information is important to us. We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100 percent secure, however. Therefore, while we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.

**Business Transitions**  
In the event the Company goes through a business transition, such as a merger, acquisition by another company or sale of all or a portion of its assets, your personally identifiable information will likely be among the assets transferred.

**Changes in this Privacy Statement**  
If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes to this privacy statement, the homepage and other places we deem appropriate so that you are aware of what information we collect, how we use it and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it.

We reserve the right to modify this privacy statement at any time, so please review it frequently. If we make material changes to this policy, we will notify you here.

**Contact Us**  
If you have any questions or suggestions regarding our privacy policy, please contact us at: 800-221-0051; [sitesupport@njng.com](mailto:sitesupport@njng.com); or 1415 Wyckoff Road, P.O. Box 1464, Wall, NJ 07719.
